<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Paessler Blog (EN)</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com</link><description></description><atom:link href="" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 11:54:22 -0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>7 Reasons Why MSPs Should Consider PRTG Hosted by Paessler</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/7-reasons-why-msps-should-consider-prtg-hosted-by-paessler</link><description>If you are an MSP (Managed Service Provider) providing IT services for customers, then a part of that service is undoubtedly network monitoring. In fact, you probably have service level agreements attached to metrics like uptime, network speeds, and so on. So you need a capable network monitoring tool to take care of this requirement.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 11:54:22 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/7-reasons-why-msps-should-consider-prtg-hosted-by-paessler</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/blog/header/prtg-in-the-cloud-benefits.png" length="63435" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>Monitoring Insights</category></item><item><title>PRTG Release 18.3.42 Is about Notifications, SQL Server 2017 and Shiny Map Objects</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/prtg-release-18.3.42-is-about-notifications-sql-server-2017-and-shiny-map-objects</link><description>I'm sure most of you are already using our PRTG release 18.2.41. Have you tried the donuts? 😉 Since the last PRTG release this graph object is available in the maps. If you really don't know this yet, take a look at the last release blog article: Mmm…Donuts! PRTG Release 18.2.41 Comes with a New Map Chart Object 
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 10:53:55 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/prtg-release-18.3.42-is-about-notifications-sql-server-2017-and-shiny-map-objects</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/blog/header/prtg-new-release-01.png" length="412870" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>4 Perceptions of AI That Are Quite Amazing</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/4-perceptions-of-ai-that-are-quite-amazing</link><description>AI will become "ASI" within the next 50 years, which is the last invention mankind has to make... Whaaaat?.... While researching AI, I’ve found some fascinating tendencies like this and other observations on AI that I would like to share. There's a lot of stuff in here that's really mind-blowing.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2018 09:53:48 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/4-perceptions-of-ai-that-are-quite-amazing</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/000502-4-perceptions-AI.RZ.png" length="105031" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>Life, the Universe and Everything</category></item><item><title>A Day without Sysadmins. What Could Possibly Go Wrong?</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/1-day-without-admin.-what-could-possibly-go-wrong</link><description>Today is Sysadmin Appreciation Day, so we thought we'd give our own sysadmins a day off. Because as much as we appreciate their work, we believed we could manage at least one full day without them. At least that's what we thought.</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2018 09:21:25 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/1-day-without-admin.-what-could-possibly-go-wrong</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/sysadmin-appreciation-day.png" length="139568" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>At the Paessler Office</category></item><item><title>Monitoring Healthcare IT With PRTG: A Video</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/monitoring-healthcare-it-with-prtg-a-video</link><description>RIS, LIMS, HIS, PACS...the technology of modern healthcare has its own language, and along with it, its own IT requirements. If you've been following our recent healthcare posts, you'll know that we've already discussed the digitalization of healthcare IT, and how healthcare IT can be monitored.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jul 2018 11:54:42 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/monitoring-healthcare-it-with-prtg-a-video</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/blog/2018-03/digitization-healthcare-sector.png" length="39272" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>Monitoring Insights</category></item><item><title>Monitor Your Palo Alto Firewall with PRTG</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/monitor-your-palo-alto-firewall-with-prtg</link><description>
You are probably familiar with Palo Alto Networks based in Santa Clara, California, who provide their 45,000+ customers in over 150 countries a "Next-Generation Security Platform" through their firewalls and security management tools. But did you know that PRTG can monitor the critical aspects of a Palo Alto device quickly and easily?
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 13:02:58 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/monitor-your-palo-alto-firewall-with-prtg</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/blog/header/header-palo-alto-firewalls.png" length="512173" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>Monitoring Insights</category></item><item><title>3 Companies That Realize IoT in a Completely Different Way. A Creative Pool of Possibilities.</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/3-companies-that-realize-iot-in-a-completely-different-way</link><description>IoT is an important topic in our blog because, well, it's just a damn important emerging field. And the most interesting thing about IoT is that it has so many forms, so many possibilities to realize a digitization of work, private life, or industry. Here are 3 cool realizations of companies, who either think big in their vision or are very individual.</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 14:06:06 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/3-companies-that-realize-iot-in-a-completely-different-way</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/3-Companies-Discover-IoT.png" length="82926" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>IT Insights</category></item><item><title>5 PRTG Customer Stories You Might Not Know</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/prtg-customer-stories</link><description>We're always fascinated by how PRTG is used out there in the wild. With over 200,000 PRTG users worldwide, you can imagine that there are some pretty cool use cases. Some we don't even know about. For the ones we do know about, we like to write them down and tell their stories. As an example: just recently, we featured a sensor contest, and what we got back was nothing short of amazing to us. The winner was a smart mailbox (seriously, you need to check it out), but some of the other sensor stories were also eye-openers for us.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2018 11:41:26 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/prtg-customer-stories</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/blog/2018-07/case-study-roundup.png" length="84862" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>5 Common Risks of Shadow IT and How to Gain Control of It</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/5-common-risks-of-shadow-it-and-how-to-gain-control-of-it</link><description>Surely every administrator has heard of shadow IT, and probably many of you admins live in (peaceful) coexistence with these parallel, partly unknown IT infrastructures.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2018 11:42:17 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/5-common-risks-of-shadow-it-and-how-to-gain-control-of-it</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/blog/header/shadow-it.png" length="10682" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>IT Insights</category></item><item><title>The EU Has Understood the Issue of IoT Security... Seriously</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/the-eu-has-understood-the-issue-of-iot-security</link><description>As we have already described in previous articles, the topic of IoT security is something that is explosive. Of course, if we live in a functional smart home at some point, we would like the devices that know everything about us not to fall into the hands of the bad guys. With the new EU-funded innovation project "Protecting Digital Industries" on security for the Internet of Things, the government wants to make the digital world safer. The project runs until December 2020 and is funded by the EU's Horizon 2020 research and innovation program. Fujitsu is in charge of the project. </description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2018 09:39:19 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/the-eu-has-understood-the-issue-of-iot-security</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/iot-security-fujitsu.png" length="68989" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>IT Insights</category></item><item><title>How Do I Find the Best Time to Air Out an Overheated Room (Using PRTG)?</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/how-do-i-find-the-best-time-to-aerate-an-overheated-room-with-prtg</link><description>Summer is here again, and in addition to lots of sunshine, happy people and a holiday feeling, it also brings hot temperatures. As nice as a heat wave may be (if you lie at the pool with a cocktail), intrusive temperature values in living rooms or bedrooms are unpleasant.</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 11:57:35 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/how-do-i-find-the-best-time-to-aerate-an-overheated-room-with-prtg</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/blog/header/header-netatmo-und-prtg-temperatur-ueberwachung.jpg" length="84433" type="image/jpeg"></enclosure><category>All About PRTG</category></item><item><title>Maker Monday: Making a Temperature Logger</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/maker-monday-temperature-logger</link><description>If you've been following our previous Maker Monday projects, you will know that we just finished putting together a wake up light.&amp;nbsp;For our newest Maker Monday project, we decided to make a temperature logger (which will also measure humidity and air pressure). Part 1 (of 2) has just gone live on our&amp;nbsp;Paessler YouTube channel! Here's what we did.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 14:58:47 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/maker-monday-temperature-logger</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/blog/header/Maker-Monday.png" length="427615" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>IT Insights</category></item><item><title>The 1.5 Billion Dollar Market: IoT Security</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/investments-in-iot-security-are-set-to-increase-rapidly-in-2018</link><description>We recently showed in a blog article that the topic of security should enjoy a high status in the context of IoT, but that this is often not (yet) the case. IoT devices are frequently largely without any protection. Even if they are quite uninteresting for attack scenarios such as ransomware, the security issues in connection with smart devices remain an explosive topic. The devices are relatively easy to manipulate so that users can be spied on or information stolen.</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2018 10:37:10 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/investments-in-iot-security-are-set-to-increase-rapidly-in-2018</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/IOT-Security-Finance.png" length="137595" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>IT Insights</category></item><item><title>Patient Uninterrupted: 4 Things in Healthcare IT that Must be Monitored</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/patient-uninterrupted-4-things-in-healthcare-it-that-must-be-monitored</link><description>In recent years, medical healthcare infrastructure has gone through digitization, just as many other industries have. The IoT has brought an array of new connected medical devices that are revolutionizing the medical field. This digitization has led to medical devices and the traditional IT infrastructure becoming more and more intertwined. This subsequently means that medical IT has more points of failure than ever before.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jul 2018 14:22:52 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/patient-uninterrupted-4-things-in-healthcare-it-that-must-be-monitored</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/blog/2018-03/digitization-healthcare-sector.png" length="39272" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>Monitoring Insights</category></item><item><title>Manage Large-Scaled PRTG Environments with Savision</title><link>https://blog.paessler.com/manage-large-scaled-prtg-environments-with-savision</link><description>Managing large-scale and multifaceted PRTG installations with tens of thousands of sensors in many locations across the globe requires administrators with deep knowledge and experience. Especially in such complex environments, a simple management of large systems is the holy grail for admins. Today we want to look at Savision's solution, which eases the management of very complex system environments - PLUS,&amp;nbsp;register for our Savision Webinar on July 12th.
</description><author>info@paessler.com (Paessler)</author><pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2018 09:58:32 -0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.paessler.com/manage-large-scaled-prtg-environments-with-savision</guid><enclosure url="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hubfs/2990530/blog/header/blogheader-prtg-and-savision.png" length="26852" type="image/png"></enclosure><category>Admin's Toolbox</category></item></channel></rss>
